{
  "theme": [
    {
      "Questions": {
        "theme": [
          {
            "Question": "What is the largest living primate in the world?",
            "TrueAnswer": "Gorilla",
            "FalseAnswer": [
              "Orangutan",
              "Chimpanzee",
              "Baboon"
            ],
            "Explanation": "Gorillas are the largest living primates and are ground-dwelling herbivores native to the forests of central sub-Saharan Africa."
          },
          {
            "Question": "Which big cat is the fastest runner on land?",
            "TrueAnswer": "Cheetah",
            "FalseAnswer": [
              "Lion",
              "Jaguar",
              "Leopard"
            ],
            "Explanation": "Cheetahs are the fastest land animals, capable of reaching speeds between 50-80 mph in short bursts covering distances up to 1,500 ft."
          },
          {
            "Question": "What is the main diet of a giant panda?",
            "TrueAnswer": "Bamboo",
            "FalseAnswer": [
              "Fish",
              "Berries",
              "Insects"
            ],
            "Explanation": "Giant pandas primarily feed on bamboo, consuming up to 26-84 pounds per day due to their low nutritional value, resulting in significant time foraging."
          },
          {
            "Question": "What sea turtle is the largest and heaviest?",
            "TrueAnswer": "Leatherback",
            "FalseAnswer": [
              "Loggerhead",
              "Hawksbill",
              "Green Turtle"
            ],
            "Explanation": "The leatherback sea turtle is the largest and heaviest of all sea turtle species, with adults reaching lengths of 6-7 feet and weights around 550-1,540 lb."
          },
          {
            "Question": "Which bird has the largest wingspan?",
            "TrueAnswer": "Wandering Albatross",
            "FalseAnswer": [
              "Bald Eagle",
              "Andean Condor",
              "California Condor"
            ],
            "Explanation": "The Wandering Albatross holds the record for the largest wingspan of any living bird, measuring up to 11 feet from tip to tip."
          },
          {
            "Question": "How many tigers subspecies are considered extinct?",
            "TrueAnswer": "3",
            "FalseAnswer": [
              "1",
              "5",
              "7"
            ],
            "Explanation": "Three subspecies of tigers—the Bali, Caspian, and Javan—are considered extinct due to habitat loss and hunting."
          },
          {
            "Question": "Which species is known as 'the living fossil'?",
            "TrueAnswer": "Coelacanth",
            "FalseAnswer": [
              "Giant Panda",
              "Platypus",
              "Red Panda"
            ],
            "Explanation": "The Coelacanth is often referred to as 'the living fossil' because it is believed to be an ancient species that has remained almost unchanged for 400 million years."
          },
          {
            "Question": "What iconic marine animal is critically endangered due to illegal fishing?",
            "TrueAnswer": "Vaquita",
            "FalseAnswer": [
              "Narwhal",
              "Beluga Whale",
              "Dolphin"
            ],
            "Explanation": "The vaquita, a small porpoise native to the Gulf of California, is critically endangered due to accidental entanglement in illegal gillnets used to catch the totoaba fish."
          },
          {
            "Question": "Which member of the ape family is closest to humans?",
            "TrueAnswer": "Bonobo",
            "FalseAnswer": [
              "Gibbon",
              "Orangutan",
              "Gorilla"
            ],
            "Explanation": "The bonobo, along with the common chimpanzee, is the closest extant relative to humans, sharing approximately 98.7% of its DNA with humans."
          },
          {
            "Question": "What is the world’s most trafficked mammal for traditional medicine?",
            "TrueAnswer": "Pangolin",
            "FalseAnswer": [
              "Armadillo",
              "Anteater",
              "Aardvark"
            ],
            "Explanation": "The pangolin is the most trafficked mammal due to the illegal trade of its scales and meat for traditional medicine and consumption in Asia and Africa."
          },
          {
            "Question": "Which marine mammal holds the title of the world’s largest mammal?",
            "TrueAnswer": "Blue Whale",
            "FalseAnswer": [
              "Humpback Whale",
              "Sperm Whale",
              "Killer Whale"
            ],
            "Explanation": "The blue whale, an oceanic marvel, holds the title of the world’s largest mammal, with adult individuals reaching lengths of up to 100 feet and weights of 200 tons."
          },
          {
            "Question": "What is the main threat to the survival of polar bears?",
            "TrueAnswer": "Climate Change",
            "FalseAnswer": [
              "Hunting",
              "Oil Spills",
              "Habitat Loss"
            ],
            "Explanation": "Climate change poses the greatest threat to polar bears, impacting their habitat and reducing sea ice cover essential for hunting and reproduction."
          },
          {
            "Question": "Which big cat is known for its solitary and elusive nature?",
            "TrueAnswer": "Snow Leopard",
            "FalseAnswer": [
              "Jaguar",
              "Leopard",
              "Cheetah"
            ],
            "Explanation": "The snow leopard is known for its solitary and elusive nature, inhabiting remote, rugged mountain ranges in Central and South Asia."
          },
          {
            "Question": "What is the estimated number of African elephants lost to poaching within a decade?",
            "TrueAnswer": "100,000",
            "FalseAnswer": [
              "50,000",
              "200,000",
              "300,000"
            ],
            "Explanation": "An estimated 100,000 African elephants were lost to poaching for their ivory tusks between 2010 and 2020, making this species vulnerable to extinction."
          },
          {
            "Question": "Which ape species is only found in one country in the world?",
            "TrueAnswer": "Mountain Gorilla",
            "FalseAnswer": [
              "Chimpanzee",
              "Bornean Orangutan",
              "Bonobo"
            ],
            "Explanation": "The mountain gorilla is found only in the Virunga Mountains of Central Africa, shared between Rwanda, Uganda, and the Democratic Republic of the Congo."
          },
          {
            "Question": "What is the primary reason for the decline of the Sumatran rhinoceros population?",
            "TrueAnswer": "Habitat Loss",
            "FalseAnswer": [
              "Poaching",
              "Disease",
              "Climate Change"
            ],
            "Explanation": "The primary reason for the decline in Sumatran rhinoceros population is habitat loss due to deforestation and human encroachment, leading to habitat fragmentation and reduced breeding pairs."
          },
          {
            "Question": "Which species is the most heavily trafficked reptile globally?",
            "TrueAnswer": "Ploughshare Tortoise",
            "FalseAnswer": [
              "Galapagos Tortoise",
              "Leopard Tortoise",
              "Aldabra Giant Tortoise"
            ],
            "Explanation": "The ploughshare tortoise is the most heavily trafficked reptile globally, threatened by illegal collection for the pet trade and habitat destruction in its native region of Madagascar."
          },
          {
            "Question": "What is the biggest threat to the survival of the Amur leopard?",
            "TrueAnswer": "Habitat Loss",
            "FalseAnswer": [
              "Poaching",
              "Climate Change",
              "Hunting"
            ],
            "Explanation": "The biggest threat to the survival of the Amur leopard is habitat loss and fragmentation, primarily due to human activities such as logging, forest fires, and development projects."
          },
          {
            "Question": "Which marine animal is the most endangered cetacean species in the world?",
            "TrueAnswer": "Vaquita",
            "FalseAnswer": [
              "Hector's Dolphin",
              "Blue Whale",
              "Orca"
            ],
            "Explanation": "The vaquita, a small porpoise endemic to the northern Gulf of California, is the most endangered cetacean species in the world, with less than 10 individuals remaining due to bycatch in illegal gillnets."
          }
        ]
      }
    }
  ]
}